vch.ca 2005-12-26

# Privacy Statement & Terms of Use - Vancouver Coastal Health

  * Privacy Statement and Terms of Use
  * What is Personal Information?
  * What Personal Information is Collected?
  * How is Personal Information Used?
  * How is Personal Information Disclosed?
  * Links to Other Websites
  * Copyright/Permission to Reproduce
  * Representation and Provision of Information
  * Security
  * Your Consent and Acceptance of these Terms
  * Contact Us
  * Privacy Legislation

### Privacy Statement and Terms of Use

Vancouver Coastal Health (VCH) is firmly committed to maintaining confidentiality, respects personal privacy, and as a public body under the BC Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (FOIPPA), is responsible for the protection of all personal information under its custody and control.

This Privacy Statement and Terms of Use document outlines the information practices for this website, including what type of personal information is collected, used, and to whom the information is disclosed.

Please read this document before providing any personal information.

### What is Personal Information? 

Under FOIPPA, personal information is any recorded information on an identifiable individual. This can include, but is not limited to, an individual’s name, address, telephone number, age, identifying number, fingerprints, blood type, health care history, education, financial, criminal, or employment history.

### What Personal Information is Collected?

As a visitor to this website, you are anonymous to the organization. VCH does not automatically collect personally identifiable information from visitor’s to this website. 

There may be situations where personal information is requested. However, we obtain this information only when you provide it voluntarily for a specific purpose through, for example, requesting information via e-mail, completing forms, or registering in a secure portion of the website.

All personal information collected will be kept confidential.

### How is Personal Information Used?

VCH only uses your personal information for responding to and processing your requests for information. Personal information collected will only be used for the specific purpose for which you provided the information and will not be made available to others for any other purpose.

### How is Personal Information Disclosed?

Unless required or permitted by law, any personal information that you provide will not be disclosed beyond the organization. It is shared internally only to fulfill the specific purpose for which you provided the information.

When required by law, VCH will disclose any information it deems appropriate and necessary, for example, in connection with legal proceedings or claims of copyright infringement, or other unlawful acts associated with the visitor’s use of this website, or if express consent is obtained from the individual.

### Links to Other Websites

The VCH website will contain links to other websites. By providing these links, VCH is not endorsing these websites nor is it responsible for the privacy practices, content, transactions, and the functioning of the websites.

### Copyright/Permission to Reproduce

Unless otherwise noted, the content of the VCH website is for visitor's personal and non-commercial use. The materials and images on this website are protected by copyright and are trademarked. Advanced, written authorization is required from VCH if you wish to use and/or publish the name, logo, photo, and/or likeness, photographs, graphics, illustrations, video, music and sound from VCH's website. **For more information on our authorization and release policies please contact Kathleen Butler in VCH's Communications Department at[kathleen.butler@vch.ca](mailto:kathleen.butler@vch.ca) or phone 604.708.5281. **

Unless otherwise noted, text on this website may be reproduced for non-commercial personal purposes. Further, any reproductions may not be represented as an official version of the materials reproduced, or as having been made in affiliation with, or with the endorsement of VCH.

### Representation and Provision of Information

VCH undertakes reasonable efforts to provide accurate and current information on its website, but assumes no responsibility for omissions and inaccuracy of website materials. The mention of specific products or services on this website does not constitute or imply a recommendation or endorsement by VCH, unless explicitly stated. 

VCH assumes no responsibility or liability for any claims of direct, indirect, special, incidental, consequential, or other damages based on any use of this website or any other website to which this site is linked.

If you have specific questions or health concerns, please consult a physician.

### Security

VCH is committed to protecting your personal information and has appropriate physical, technical, and administrative measures in place to protect your personal information.

### Your Consent and Acceptance of these Terms

By agreeing to use this site and providing personal information, you acknowledge reading the Privacy Statement and Terms of Use and agree with its terms including the collection, use, and disclosure of such information. 

The Statement and Terms of Use are not intended to and do not create any contractual or other legal rights in or on behalf of any party. VCH reserves the right to update this policy at any time and will notify users with a statement on the website. Users are responsible for reviewing this document periodically for changes.

**This statement was last revised on: July 25, 2005.**

### Contact the Privacy and Security Office

VCH welcomes your comments and questions about our Privacy Statement and Terms of Use. Please contact the Information Privacy and Security Office at Vancouver Coastal Health at 604.875.5568 or e-mail: [privacy@vch.ca](mailto:privacy@vch.ca).

For inquiries unrelated to the privacy office, please contact [feedback@vch.ca](mailto:feedback@vch.ca).

### Privacy Legislation

For more information on the BC Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (FOIPPA) and how you can protect the privacy of your personal information, please refer to the Office of the Information and Privacy Commissioner of British Columbia. Call 250.387.5629 or refer to: [www.oipcbc.org](http://www.oipcbc.org/).
